BRANDON SASSIN

SUMMARY

Proven Web Developer and Technical Support Specialist with 2+ years of experience as a Developer/Designer and 5+ years of experience as a Technical Support Specialist. In my current role as a Developer/Designer at Chitra Productions, I develop software and websites for DoD contracts using technologies such as: Node.js, Angular, JavaScript, AWS Amplify. As a dedicated lifelong learner always seeking to improve my coding skills, I have undergone 500+ hours of online instruction through Udemy and Pluralsight (Codeschool). Recently focusing on ReactJS and other trending software. I am now looking to continue my career by joining a team of passionate, communicative, and detail oriented professionals where I can meaningfully contribute to the ultimate satisfaction of the end user.

SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, Javascript, CSS, **TypeScript**
- Frameworks: Angular
- Runtime Environment: Node.is
- Libraries: React, ¡Query, Tailwind CSS
- Databases: MySQL, AWS, Google **Firebase**
- Authorization: OAuth, AWS, Firebase Authentication
- CICD: GIT

In a developer role at your company I will...

- Code within company coding standards and styles.
- Test code for accuracy and error tolerance.
- Ability to communicate and work in a team environment.
- Build responsive frontend designs to spec per the UX design.
- Build out API routes per RESTful design structure.
- Diligently prioritize multiple projects to ensure timely results.
- Be coachable and accepting of constructive criticism.
- Provide problem solving skills to prioritize, identify, and resolve issues.

EXPERIENCE

Chitra Productions - Developer/Designer

Norfolk, VA Feb 2021 - Present

I am a member of the development team for a highly reputable and award-winning woman-owned Defense Department contractor. Our company has successfully completed numerous contracts and has earned a strong reputation in the industry

- Designed and assisted in the development of a summer internship application using Node.is, Angular, and AWS Amplify, with the capability to store hundreds of thousands of users in a secure database. I am responsible for handling emergency fixes and will be responsible for maintaining updates to the application for the next 4 years.
- As part of a small team, I contributed to the development of 200+ hours of trainee courses using Adobe Captivate, which required knowledge of JavaScript and CSS

DevLime Labs LLC - Developer/Designer

Chesapeake, VA Feb 2021 - Present

As part of a four-person team, collaborated to update and maintain legacy software for clients who no longer have access to their original developers. Contributing to the development of multiple, long term, customized software solutions designed to meet specific end-user specifications.

- Assisting in the development of a cyber security product by implementing updates to the front end user interface.
- Contributing to the development of a proprietary company product by providing ideas, as well as implementing updates to the front and back end using various technologies such as Node.js, Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, and Google Firebase.

EDUCATION

Treehouse Remote 2016 - 2017

Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, and overall website development including Wordpress and other commonly used CMS.

Pluralsight (Codeschool)

Advanced HTML, CSS, PHP and Javascript.

Udemy Remote 2020 - Present

Advanced Javascript, ReactJS, and Angular.

Remote 2016 - 2018